Gregory Kelleher

+353 (0)86 3690234 gregory@gregorykelleher.com

gregorykelleher.com github.com/gregorykelleher linkedin.com/in/gregorykelleher

Summary

I'm a software engineer at Jaguar Land Rover doing R&D for the latest in electrical vehicle architecture. I have a strong passion for technology, especially with respect to building embedded systems and IoT.

This is most evident from my two previous internships at Intel R&D, and most recently, in my current employment.

Working as a software engineer with both companies has enabled me to demonstrate and build upon my technical skills as well as offering me a valuable opportunity to work and collaborate with experts in the field; within a professional domain.

Outside of work, my interests in technology extend from electronics to web development. I enjoy tinkering with pet projects, and in my own time, I maintain an up-to-date website on my own VPS where I occasionally blog on what I'm doing.

Experience

Jaguar Land Rover Research & Development Ireland Ltd / Software Engineer AUG 2018 - CURR, SHANNON

Currently working across a broad software domain that encompasses both research and production projects.

Extensive experience writing modern C++ for next-generation Electrical Vehicle Architecture (EVA). Strong focus on delivering ASIL-D rated software with strict compliance to MISRA and AutoSAR coding standards.

Long-term involvement on the Land Rover Defender (L663) programme, developing production software to enable SOTA capabilities for network diagnostics.

Intel Research & Development Ireland Ltd / Software Engineer

FEB 2017 - AUG 2017, LEIXLIP

Intern working as part of the Strategy and Solutions Engineering Division (SSED). Conducted study into the role for Information Security in relation to IoT. Special focus into Direct Anonymous Attestation (DAA) algorithms, as well as cryptographic protocols such as TLS/SSL.

Familiarity with OpenSSL and implementing TLS/SSL best practices, e.g. HSTS, HPKP, ECDHE, HTTP/2, OCSP stapling, forward secrecy .etc

Intel Research & Development Ireland Ltd / Software Engineer

MAY 2016 - SEPT 2016, LEIXLIP

Summer internship working with embedded systems and microcontrollers as part of Quark Solutions Division (QSD). Built proficiency in C with GNU toolchain, alongside debugging tools such as GDB and OpenOCD, as well as VCS (Git and Gerrit).

Proficiencies

• Systems and Embedded Programming

- o Modern C++14 and above, ANSI C
- o CMake and Conan
- Google Test
- Git and GNU toolchain (gcc, gcov, gdb .etc)

Debugging and Analysis

- Valgrind
- o Clang-tidy and Cppcheck
- LDRA
- o OpenOCD

• Operating Systems and Platforms

- Linux and QNX (Micro-kernel UNIX)
- Yocto Project and BitBake
- Numerous (x86/ARM) evaluation boards
- o Intel Quark and Atom (Atlas Peak and Denverton)

DevOps and Web

- GitLab Runner with Docker
- Vagrant with Packer and Ansible
- NGINX and Caddy web-server using DigitalOcean
- SQL and Firebase databasing

Education

Maynooth University / B.Sc. Computer Science and Software Engineering

SEPT 2014 - MAY 2018

College project - <u>demo</u> - <u>github</u>

Member of Computer Science Society

References

Peter Barry / Chief Software Architect / Jaguar Land Rover R&D

Upon Request

Mike Hibbett / Senior Solution Architect / Taoglas

Upon Request